傲骨之战
第一季 第二集
贱货
Bitch.
该死的贱货
Fucking bitch.
我知道你住哪
I know where you live.
我知道你家人住哪
I know where your family...
玛娅·林德尔你听着
This is for Maia Rindell.
我要把你和你那个蕾丝边女朋友都强奸了
I'm gonna rape you and your dyke girl...
早上好
Hi. Good morning.
去死吧  你偷了我的钱
And fuck you. You stole my money.
我只想让你尝尝我受的苦
I just want you to hurt like I do.
语音信箱
未知号码
你好  我第一天上班
Hi, it's my first day here.
不太清楚我该去哪
And, uh, I'm not too sure where to g...
库克县维护者
林德尔骗局可能...
-玛娅·林德尔  -是我
- Maia Rindell? - Yes!
你还好吗
You okay?
没事  只是
Yes! Just, um...
朱利叶斯·凯恩
Julius Cain.
我是这里的管理合伙人
I'm the managing partner here.
我带你去你的办公桌
Let me show you to your desk.
我们有55个同事以及40个工位
We have 55 associates and 40 work stations,
所以我们采用公用办公桌系统
so we employ a hot desk system.
公共区域闲置座位都可占用
Occupy any empty chair in the communal area,
但记得笔记本得随身携带  因为等你回来
but keep your laptop with you because you might be returning
可能要换其他地方
to a different space when you come back.
坐吧
Go ahead.
好
Good.
10点  我需要你去仓库与商场销售人员工会
At 10:00, I'm gonna need you at the SWSMU offices,
所以20分钟后到接待处和我碰面
so meet me at reception in 20 minutes.
什么地方
The what?
仓库与商场销售人员工会
SWSMU.
我们的工会合同之一
One of our union contracts.
每月一次  我们给他们成员提供法律援助
Once a month, we offer their members pro bono service
作为他们给律师费的服务
as part of our retainer.
20分钟
20 minutes.
未知号码
我要强奸你  再把你的奶子切掉
你听到了吗  戴安
Did you hear that, Diane?
我  听到了  我只是不敢相信
I... yes. I just can't believe it.
他们扣留了我的认购金
They're withholding my capital contribution?
他们说必须对你的任期进行审查
They say they have to review your tenure.
什么任期  我是冠名合伙人
What tenure?! I was a name partner.
我创办的律所
I created that firm.
那是我的钱
It's my money.
我很抱歉  戴安
I'm sorry, Diane.
我还有钱吗
Do I have any reserves?
如果你把房子卖了
If you sell your apartment.
我不能这么做
I can't do that.
你总可以和你的新合伙人谈谈
Well, you can always talk to your new partners,
看他们能不能给你提供贷款
and see if they'll offer you a loan.
我们试过给你家里打电话
We tried to call you at home.
有什么事
Because?
我们把你搬到大厅边上了
We're moving you down the hall.
有新合伙人要来
There's a new partner.
我们得腾个地方出来
We have to make room.
戴安
Diane?
没错
Yep.
看  也不是很糟
See, it's not so bad.
多么温馨的小窝
Home sweet home.
我需要你今早去趟仓库与商场销售人员工会
Oh, and I'm gonna need you at the SWSMU this morning.
为什么
Why?
我上个月去过了
I did it last month.
没错  你也做得非常漂亮
Yes, and you were so good at it, too.
早上好
Good morning.
莎瑞瑟
Sharise.
来  来接啊  来接啊
Come on, come get this. Come get this.
来接啊
Come get this!
大学选的怎么样了
How that college search coming?
累坏了  双胞胎  你懂的
Ah, all-consuming. Twins, you know.
没错  我听到了
Yeah, I hear you.
肯德尔案那边有什么动静
Any word on the Kendall offer?
他们今早打过电话
They called this morning.
谁  大卫·李
Who? David Lee?
没错  先生
Yes, sir.
我们要拿到我们那600万了
We're getting our six mill
戴安来了吗
Diane here yet?
来了  她和芭芭拉在一起
Yeah, she's in with Barbara.
跟芭芭拉一起
She is, huh?
我几年前在律师协会上听过你发言
I heard you speak at an ABA conference a few years ago.
没错  关于种族招聘话题吗
Oh, yes. On racial hiring?
没错
That's right.
我希望我没让自己太难堪
Oh, well, I hope I didn't embarrass myself too much.
也没有很了
Hmm, not too much.
戴安·洛哈特
Diane Lockhart.
我感觉现在我们也有
I feel like we acquired
自己的吉米·巴特勒了
our very own Jimmy Butler right here.
美国职业篮球运动员  效力于NBA芝加哥公牛队
阿德里安  你好吗
Adrian, how are you?
很好
Good, good.
一点见面礼
A little gift for you.
泉藤湖酒
Spring Arbor Lake Wine,
我自己的标  2006年
my very own label, 2006.
你有自己的酒庄吗
You have a winery?
就是一排葡萄藤而已  就这些  坐吧
Ah, just a row of vines, that's all. Sit, sit.
你们俩谈的怎么样
So how's everything going with you two?
芭芭拉告诉你大概情况了吗
Barbara give you the rundown?
没错
She did.
你们俩相处的好吗
Are you two playing nice?
-挺好的  阿德里安  -那就好
- We are, Adrian. - Good.
顺便提个内务问题
Oh, by the way, just a housekeeping matter,
我们下个礼拜需要你的认购金
but we'll need your capital contribution by next week.
这事该提的
Oh, yes, of course.
但我得说明一下
Just so you know,
我旧律所有点不太配合
my old firm is being a bit intransigent.
大卫·李  那家伙太有意思了
Yeah, David Lee. Wonderful guy.
所以  希望你能稍微宽限一下
So, um, if you don't mind being a bit patient.
当然
Of course.
但是听着  我需要你
But listen, I'll need you
11点和我们的诉讼投资人
in 11:00 A.M. Meeting to pitch cases
开会挑选案件
to our litigation financiers.
好的  我们到时见
Right. Well, good. I'll see you there.
好的
You will.
戴安
Diane.
-欢迎加入  -谢谢
- Welcome. - Thank you.
我们要宽限她多长时间
And how patient are we to be?
给她两周时间吧
Let's give her two weeks.
你好
Hello?
只是给你电脑插个电
Just plugging in your computer.
你是洛哈特&德克尔律所派来的吗
Are you from Lockhart, Deckler?
李&莱曼&德克尔&古斯曼
Lee, Lyman, Deckler, Gussman...
我的名字撤下得挺快的
Well, that didn't take them very long.
没错  一群混蛋
I know. Bunch of assholes.
梅丽莎
Marissa?
没错  你好
Yeah, hey.
要我把所有东西弄好吗
Want me to set up anything else?
-不用了  我自己来  -不  我来吧
- No, I can do it. - No, let me.
如果我回的太早
If I get back too quick,
他们只会再安排差事给我
they'll just send me out on another errand.
我先把这些挂起来
Here, I'll hang these.
艾丽西娅雇我时  本来是让我
When Alicia hired me, I was supposed to be involved
参与案子之类的
in cases and everything,
但她走了之后我就只是个搬箱子什么的
but it's been all moving boxes since she left.
这个还要吗
Still want this?
当然要
Definitely.
这些你想挂哪儿
And, uh, where do you want these?
-这是什么  -非洲面具
- What are those? - African masks.
这我知道  可它从哪儿来的
Well, I can see that. Where are they from?
你办公室
Your office.
不可能
No.
大卫·李  真好笑
David Lee. Very funny.
顺便一提
By the way,
我知道你还需要助理  戴安
I know you still need an assistant, Diane.
你好
Hello.
这是梅丽莎
Uh, this is Marissa,
我原来律所派来的人
from my old firm.
嗨  我是来送东西的
Hi. Just dropping stuff off.
今天有几个新人过来
Well, I have a few people coming in today
应聘助理职位
for possible assistants.
我会叫他们过来
I'll send them by.
谢谢
Thank you.
我不想自吹自擂
Okay, I don't want to sound self-serving here,
但我觉得雇我是最明智的
but I think it's a smart move for you to hire me.
我知道了
Oh, good to know.
-谢谢  -说真的  你需要助理
- Thank you. - No, seriously. You need an assistant.
我什么都能做
I can do whatever you want around here,
而且我要得不多  你能开多少薪水
and I'm not that expensive. What are you paying?
把你的简历留下就好  梅丽莎
Why don't you just leave your resume, Marissa?
我没简历
I don't have one.
反正我真人比简历好多了
I'm much better in person, anyway.
就雇我一天
Look, just hire me for one day,
等你找到更好的人选就可以换掉我
just until you get someone better.
我向你保证  你找不到更好的
And I promise you won't get someone better.
仓库与商场销售人员工会
本地组织
把法律援助咨询时间
You limit your pro bono consultations
限制在每人20分钟以内
to 20 minutes each.
如果要解决他们的法律问题需要更多时间
If their legal issues require more time,
去找卢卡
go to Lucca.
由她来批准是否需要更多时间
She will sign off on more time.
记住  你们来这里
Remember, you're only here
是提供法律咨询的  而不是来工作
to offer legal advice, not legal work.
别被缠住了  如果可以
Don't get tied down. Move people on
把他们推荐到其他法律渠道去
into other legal resources when you can.
公诉辩护或者法律援助都行
Prairie State or Legal Assistance.
你们就是电梯里的关门按钮
You're the "door close" button in the elevator.
令人安慰  但不一定有多大作用
Comforting, but not necessarily effective.
我们开始吧
Here we go.
会友们  听我说  听我说
Okay, members, listen up, listen up.
仓库与商场销售人员工会
了解你的权力  在今天获取免费法律咨询
记住这些律师是以工会支持者的身份过来
Remember these lawyers are here as union advocates,
所以请把问题限制在工作事宜上
so please limit your questions to workplace matters.
只限于工作事宜
Only workplace matters.
趁着工作日午休时间来的请举手
Okay, who is here on their work break, please raise your hand.
得了吧
Oh, come on.
多尼  我知道今天是你的休息日
Donny, I know it's your day off.
把手放下
Get your hand down.
咨询只限在午休的人
Only people on their lunch break.
别乱举手  你们这样只会损害
Come on, you're only screwing over
你工会的兄弟姐妹的权益
your union brother and sister.
好的  那些在午休的人上台来
Good. Those on lunch break, come on up to the stage.
在每桌前排队  开始吧
Line up for each desk. Let's go.
你真要我去找别人吗
You're seriously telling me I have to go to someone else
我午休时间就这么点
on my lunch break?
事情是这样的  女士  我们不是过来
The thing is, ma'am, we're not really here
解决家庭法问题的  但我能介绍你去
to help with family law issues, but, uh, I can refer you to...
他不交抚养费
He's not paying child support!
我要怎么维持生计呢
How am I supposed to make ends meet
他不交抚养费
if he won't pay child support?
我懂  我很抱歉  只是
I know, I'm sorry. It's just...
我不应该提供这方面的帮助
Well, I'm not really supposed to help with...
那你过来干什么
Then why are you here?
如果你不能帮忙  你过来干什么
If you can't help, why are you here?
我需要帮助
I need help.
你好
Hello.
拜托
Oh, come on.
我来帮忙
I'm gonna help you out here.
谢谢
Thank you.
先生  你要去我的桌子吗
Sir, would you like to come to my desk?
不用  我这队挺好
No, I'm good here.
我有三年从业经验
I'm a third-year associate.
她才拿到资格证
She just passed the bar.
没关系
That's okay.
我就排这里
I'm sticking.
下一位
Next?
一周只有400美元  我过不下去
I, I just can't survive on $400 a week.
我付不起房租
I can't pay for my rent.
付不起前妻的抚养费
I can't pay for my ex-wife.
他们没照税后收入来调整发薪
And they're not adjusting it for after taxes.
而是按总收入直接扣了
They're just taking it right off the top.
我很抱歉  我不太明白
I-I'm sorry, I don't understand.
你一周工资是400美元吗
You're...you're being paid $400 a week?
对  等等  不是
Yeah. Wait, no.
我房租是这两倍  好吗
And my rent is twice that. Okay?
你要接电话吗
Do you need to get that?
不用
No.
吃屎去吧  臭婊子
不用  总有各种消息
Uh, no. It does that.
我手机也是
Yeah, mine, too.
我曾经还会收到些好消息
You know, I used to get some good news,
但现在  我觉得都是些坏消息
but now I feel like it's all bad.
我都不想回复它们
I don't even like answering it nowadays.
我很抱歉  我不太明白
So, um, I'm sorry, I'm, I'm not too sure
他们是怎么调低你薪水的
how they were able to lower your salary.
不是调低
Not lower.
是抵扣
Garnish.
他们说我偷了400双跑步鞋
They're saying that I stole 400 running shoes.
-什么  400双跑步鞋  -没错
- What? 400 running shoes? - Yeah.
他们说值七万  但那是按零售价算的
And they say that's $70,000, but that's retail,
他们又不是按零售价买的
and they don't pay retail.
而是按批发价  所以赔偿应该只有一半
They just pay wholesale, so it should be half that.
等等  抱歉  你能再说一次吗
Wait, I'm sorry. Could-could you start again?
好吧  BMI
Okay, BMI...
我在的店说我偷了400双运动鞋
...my store says that I stole 400 running shoes.
你偷了吗
And did you?
没有  我这辈子都没偷过东西
No, I've never stolen anything in my entire life.
但他们是按零售价来抵扣我薪水的
But they're garnishing my wages for the retail amount,
实际该按照批发价来扣
and it should be the wholesale amount.
那让我多赔了一倍的钱
That's double what I should pay!
但如果你没偷东西的话
But if you didn't steal anything,
为什么要让他们抵扣你的薪水
why are you letting them garnish your wages at all?
因为我签了供认书
Because I signed a confession.
我不明白  他为什么要供认
I don't understand. Why did he confess?
他们逼他这么做的
They pressured him to.
如果不签就要开除他
They threatened to fire him if he didn't.
他只是想让他们
He just wants them to charge him
以批发价算赔偿  而不是零售价
the wholesale amount and not the retail amount.
他还想为这事去仲裁吗
And he wants to go to arbitration for that?
他的合同要求他去仲裁
Well, his contract requires that he go to arbitration.
但他想让我来代理他
But he wants me to represent him.
我需要你的批准
I just need you to sign me off
再多两小时
on two more hours work.
你知道这只是无偿法援吧
You know this is just pro bono?
对吧  这只是个善意姿态而已
Right? It's a goodwill gesture.
我们不是来纠正不公的
We're not here to right a wrong.
我知道
No, I know,
但就两小时工作量而已
but it's only two hours work.
我想这样做
I want to do it.
仲裁是什么时候
When's the arbitration?
今天下午
This afternoon.
好
Okay.
祝你好运
Good luck.
你没事吧
Everything good with you?
还好
Yeah.
这些日子以来第一次感觉还行
Yeah, for the first time in a while... yes.
注意力都在别人的麻烦上对你是有好处的
It's good when you can focus on someone else's problem.
这是第一个我没被认出来的地方
First place I've been I wasn't recognized.
这是我们当务之急的案子
This is our highest priority case.
牢房里的绞刑  霍利·奥林
It's a hanging in a jail cell... Holly Orlin.
最上面你能看到「芝加哥论坛报」的一篇文章
You'll find a Chicago Tribune article on top there.
这是我这几年来看过的库克县监狱虐待案里
This is the worst Cook County jail abuse
最惨的一例
I have seen in years.
我们要求赔偿1200万
So, we're suing for $12 million,
但同时我们也希望能够在庭审前和解
but we do expect settlement before trial.
-有监控录像吗  -没有
- Any videotape? - No.
但是我们一个有非常值得同情的家庭
But we have a very sympathetic family
以及一位悲痛欲绝的寡妇
and a grieving widower.
我们需要的就是你们30万的赞助
So, all we need of your financing is $300 thousand.
不  不过谢了
No. Thanks, though.
我们的算法不看好起诉警方
Our algorithm is going cool on police suits.
你确定吗
You sure about that?
当然  还有别的吗
Mm-hmm. What else?
我想  戴安
Well, I think that, uh, Diane,
我们的新合伙人  她刚刚入伙
our newest partner... she just joined us
从洛哈特&德克尔&古斯曼过来的
from Lockhart, Deckler & Gussman...
由她来说说新案子
can speak to a new case.
我们一直在跟滥用假释权的案子
Uh, we've been looking into parole abuses.
一些假释申请因为惩罚性原因而被拒绝
Some parolees have been rejected for, uh, punitive reasons.
我认为我的合伙人担心这个方向没钱可赚
I think my partner worries there's no money there.
那取决于州政府觉得在这点上是否容易被攻击
That depends on how vulnerable the State feels.
不  取决于趋势
No. It depends on the trend.
趋势不利于你们的提议
The trend is against you.
我们明白你有自己的算法小魔咒
Look, now we understand you have your little algebraic spells,
但是我们了解整个体系
but we understand the system.
而你又能得到我们一成的收入
And you'll get ten percent of our earnings.
为什么不让我们给你赚些钱呢
Why don't you let us help you make some money?
你们还有什么
What else have you got?
玩忽职守
Malpractice?
这是一个玩忽职守诉讼案
It's a malpractice suit.
-失陪一下  -去吧
- Uh, excuse me. - Yeah.
-第二页  -什么事
- Second page. - What's wrong?
有人来找你
Someone here to see you.
丽诺·林德尔
Lenore Rindell.
在哪
Where?
你办公室
In your office.
要我打发她走吗
You want me to get rid of her?
你想要什么  丽诺
What do you need, Lenore?
我  我来找玛娅
I-I came to see Maia.
她外出了
She's out.
她不跟我说话  也不接我的电话
She's not talking to me, she's not answering my calls.
估计是她的律师不让的
My guess is her lawyer told her not to.
你能跟她谈谈吗  戴安  求你了
Can you talk to her, Diane? Please.
不行
No.
为什么
Why?
我不知道你活在什么泡沫幻境里  丽诺
I don't know what bubble you're living in, Lenore,
可是你看到我的这个办公室了吧
but you do see my office here?
你看到我还没退休吧
You do see that I am not retired,
看到我还在工作了吧
that I am still working.
不怪我们  都是贾克斯干的
This wasn't us. This was Jax.
这是他的庞氏骗局  不是我们
This is his Ponzi scheme, not ours...
你想开诚布公地谈
You want to have an honest conversation here,
那咱就谈谈  我上周找你们
then let's have it. I came to you last week
想拿回我的钱  好买我梦寐以求的房子
for my money back so that I could buy my dream house,
-你们是怎么说的来着  -我们没
- and what did you say? - We didn't...
不  我想听你说出来  你当时怎么说的
No, I want to hear you say it. What did you say?
不怪我们
This wasn't us.
你说钱放在账户里别动  用它贷款
You said keep it in your account, and borrow on it.
我本可以拿回我的钱的
I could've had my money back.
我
I...
我觉得你该走了
I think it's a good idea that you go.
戴安
Diane,
看着我
look at me.
我是无辜的
I'm innocent.
亨利是无辜的
Henry's innocent.
你是一名辩护律师
You are a defense lawyer.
你怎么就不能把对其他客户的礼节
Why can't you extend us the same courtesy
延用到我们身上
you do your other clients?
我们是被冤枉的
We are wrongly accused.
不能因为联调局说什么就是什么
Just because the Feds say it doesn't make it true.
我会告诉玛娅你来过
I'll tell Maia that you dropped by.
我知道我不该提要求  但是亨利需要你帮他
I know I shouldn't ask this, but Henry needs your help.
他在监狱里  没人愿意探望他
He's in jail and no one will visit him.
他的律师建议他认罪
His lawyer's advising him to plead guilty,
可我觉得他不应该认
but I don't think he should.
他是你的老朋友了  戴安
He's your oldest friend, Diane.
你能跟他谈谈吗
Will you talk to him?
这就跟庭审差不多吗
So it's like a trial?
是的  如实回答就行
Yes, just answer honestly.
你要做的就是这个
That's all you have to do.
我要是输了呢
And if I lose?
因为没法上诉  所以输了就是输了
Well, there's no appeal, so if you lose, you lose.
弗兰克·格文
Frank Gwinn.
到
Here.
进吧  你是律师
Go ahead. You're the lawyer?
对  雷迪克&博斯曼&科斯达律所的
Uh, yes, from Reddick, Boseman & Kolstad...
好  我是仲裁员
Good, I'm the arbiter.
咱们开始吧
Let's hear it.
这位是班吉·帝亚蒂安
And this is Benji Diyardian
BMI运动公司防损部的
from BMI's loss-prevention department.
就是他审问我的
He questioned me.
开始吧
Let's hear it.
我
I...
下午好
Good afternoon.
弗兰克的雇主  BMI运动公司
Frank's employer, BMI,
是一家市值120亿美元的运动用品商店
a sporting good store with $12 billion in assets
并且在全国各地均有经营权
and franchises throughout the country...
我不需要听这个
Yeah, I-I don't need that.
好的
Right. Um...
他们指控我的当事人
They have accused my client of stealing
从库存货物中偷窃了400双跑鞋
400 running shoes from their back-stock.
-417双  -反对
- 417. - Objection.
好吧
Okay, um,
这不是他偷的  是吗
and he didn't do it, right?
正确  先生
Uh, that is correct, sir.
他没偷
He did not do it.
你有什么事  女士
What do you need, ma'am?
我来这当工会的观察员
I'm here as an observer for the union.
为什么
Why?
我们就是想确保一切公平公正
We just want to make sure everything's fair.
好吧  这位小姐请继续
Okay, keep going, Miss.
我的当事人并没有偷鞋
My client did not steal any shoes.
他没有任何犯罪记录  然而BMI运动公司
He has no record and yet the company, BMI,
却选择克扣他将近40%的工资
have chosen to garnish his salary by almost 40%.
我们什么都没克扣  他认罪了
We didn't garnish anything, he confessed.
不  抱歉先生  会轮到你发言的
No, excuse me, sir, you'll have your chance.
这就是一家规模庞大
Um, this is a massive,
市值1200亿的公司
$12 billion company
偷窃我当事人一半的工资
stealing half my client's pay.
偷窃  别闹  我们可有他的供状登记在案
Stealing, really? We have his confession on the record.
不  他是被逼招供的
No, he was forced to confess.
有人告诉他如果他不认罪的话
He was told if he did not confess...
没人跟他说过任何事情
He was not told anything.
如果他不招认  就会被解雇
If he did not confess, then he would be fired.
弗兰克  他质问了你多久
Frank, how long did this man question you?
七个小时
Seven hours.
没有片刻休息  他被要求不能离开房间
Without break. He was told he could not leave the room.
只是因为他是一名员工  而他当时正在值班
Only because he's an employee and he was on the clock.
让我看看供词
Let me see the confession.
工会代表也想看看这个吗
Would the union rep like to see it, too?
是的  谢谢
Uh, I would, thank you.
仲裁员先生  在你看供词的同时  请记住
Mr. Arbiter, as you read that, please remember
他是被迫在这张供词上签名的
that he was forced to sign that confession.
我从没强迫过任何人  这是弗里德曼方法
I never forced anyone. This is the Friedman method.
我从未不按方法办事
I never diverged once from it at all.
什么
The what?
弗里德曼方法
The Friedman method,
这是一种质询方法
it's a process of questioning
我曾经如此训练过也得到了认证
I was trained and certified in.
先生  这是你的签名吗
Sir, is this your signature?
是的
Yes.
根据双方达成的
Then in exercise of powers conferred under Clause 25
条款中的第25条
of the agreement entered into between the parties,
本席宣布  被告胜诉
judgment is made in favor of the respondent.
等等  什么  这就完了吗
Wait, w-what? What, that's it?
谢谢大家  下次仲裁见
Thank you, I'll see the next arbitration.
但他是冤枉的
But he didn't do it!
下次仲裁见
I'll see the next arbitration.
非法监禁
False imprisonment.
仲裁员先生  我们请求仲裁再次开庭
Mr. Arbiter, we ask that the arbitration be reopened
因为被告对我当事人进行了非法监禁
based on the matter of false imprisonment.
拜托
Oh, come on...
我当事人在违背意愿的情况下被关了七小时
My client was held against his will for seven hours,
这直接违反了...所有法条
in direct contravention of... everything.
非法监禁的问题与此案无关
The issue of false imprisonment is irrelevant.
本席再次宣判  被告胜诉
Judgment is again made in favor of the respondent.
这就由不得你来判了  先生
That's not your decision to make, sir.
你说什么
Excuse me?
林德尔小姐当事人的
The arbitration agreement
仲裁协议并不包括民事侵权索赔
with Ms. Rindell's client does not cover tort claims.
而非法监禁就是一项民事侵权索赔
And false imprisonment is a tort claim.
那我们可就陷入僵局了
Then we are stalemated.
不  我们没有
No, we're not.
怎么没有
And why is that?
因为我们将会在法庭上见
Because we'll see you in court.
亨利
Henry.
你还好吗
How are you?
鲁珀特让我接受这份认罪协议
Rupert tells me I should accept a guilty plea.
20年
20 years.
你怎么想
What do you think?
我觉得很糟糕  汉克
I think this is bad, Hank.
是的  你和我  戴安
Yeah, you and I, Diane,
我们总是和对方说实话
we always told each other the truth.
不管在哪里  在大学  之后
No matter where... in college, after,
在丽诺面前
before Lenore.
我现在也要和你说实话
And I'm telling you the truth now.
我是冤枉的
I did not do this.
小亨  我应该怎么做
Hank, what am I supposed to do with that?
我破产了  分文不剩
I am bankrupted, completely.
两个月前  我聘请了一个法务会计师
Two months ago, I hired a forensics accountant
去调查贾克斯的交易
to look into Jax's trades.
有8300万美元不见了
There was $83 million missing.
那个会计师发现贾克斯把钱转移到
The accountant found Jax had moved the money
他的私人账户了
into his private account.
我试图与他对质  但还没来得及
I tried to confront him, but before I could,
贾克斯就去联调局告发了我
Jax went to the Feds to turn me in.
你应该把这些和你的律师说  不是我
You should be telling this to your lawyer, not to me.
我说了  但鲁珀特说此事无足轻重
I did, but Rupert said it doesn't matter.
对我不利的事太多了
There are too many bad facts.
好吧
Okay.
我去找找别的律师
Let me look into another lawyer.
-为什么不能是你  -不行
- Why not you? - No.
你需要一个能保持客观的人
You need someone objective.
玛娅还好吗
How's Maia?
-她做得很好  -好
- She's doing well. - Good.
她正在处理一个案子
She's on a case.
她会超越我们所有人
She's gonna blow us all away.
她见她妈妈了吗
Did she see her mom?
没有
No.
我觉得她最好远离这些事
I think it's best that she stay away
直到有个了结
until all this gets straightened out.
但这也许会需要很长时间
But that could be years.
我知道
I know.
丽诺没告诉你吗
Lenore didn't tell you?
告诉我什么
Tell me what?
她时间不多了
She doesn't have years.
她的乳腺癌复发了
Her breast cancer, it's back.
扩散到了淋巴结
Spread to her lymph nodes.
也许我该去看看她
Maybe I should go see her.
是我的话就先跟律师谈谈
I'd talk to your lawyer first.
你觉得我不应该去看她
You don't think I should go see her?
不  只是
No, it's just...
我觉得你应该谨慎一点
I think you should be careful.
她误解了我的意图
She misunderstood my intent,
也可能直接无视了  但我们没有时间纠缠这个
or she ignored it, but we just don't have time for this.
我们对律所的作为有更高的期待
And we raise expectations for what our firm can do!
卢卡
Ah, Lucca.
看来我们今早又有了新案子
It seems we picked up a new case this morning.
我和你说了我们不想
I told you we didn't want to get tangled up
这些小案子上纠缠不清
in small-ball litigation.
这并不是一个小案子
This is not small-ball.
BMI有120亿美元资产
BMI has $12 billion in assets...
是的  但我们拿不到任何惩罚性赔偿
Yes, and there won't be any punitive damages here.
-这可不好说  -这是一定的
- But we don't know that. - We do know that.
只有一个工会成员
This is one union member,
我们需要花40个计费工时
and we're about to put in 40 billable hours,
从他那得到什么  两万美元的酬劳吗
to get him what, $20,000 in back pay?
是让你把办公室让给了合伙人  所以在找事吗
Is this about you losing your office to a partner?
没有
No.
这就是个好案子
This is about a good case.
你知道弗里德曼方法是什么吗
Hey, do you know what the Friedman Method is?
弗里德曼方法
The Friedman Method?
我知道  这是一种质询
Yeah, it's a way to interrogate
嫌疑人的方法  怎么了
a suspect... why?
我有个案子
It's a case I'm on.
我怎么能了解更多点
How do I find out more about it?
简单  他们有研讨会
Easily, they have seminars.
去网上查找就好
Just look them up online.
只要你付钱  你也可以
You pay the money, and you, too,
学习怎么当警察
can learn how to be a cop.
太好了
Good to know.
好了  我得挂了  拜
Oh, okay. I got to go, bye.
我们被拒绝了
We're being shut down.
什么
What?
他们担心这案子太小了
They're worried the case is too small.
你在开玩笑吧
You're kidding.
我正要报名弗里德曼研讨会的课程
I was just about to sign up for a Friedman seminar
去继续找信息呢
to find out more.
那就去做吧
You know what, do it anyway.
工时是我们自己的
It's on our time.
为什么不做呢
Why not?
好的
Okay.
人们会说谎
People lie.
当人们说谎时
And when people lie,
他们会想坦白  这是人的本性
they want to confess... it's human nature.
你们要做的  你  你  还有你
Your job... you and you and you...
就是促成这一过程
is to enable that process.
你们是他们坦白的关键步骤
You are a crucial step to their cleansing.
你们后面的四节课上将学习
What you will learn over the next four sessions
弗里德曼方法
is the Friedman method.
一个确认罪行并让罪犯招供的方法
A way to determine guilt and obtain a confession.
这四个人中有一个在撒谎
One of these four people is lying.
他们都不承认自己从收银台那里偷了钱
They all deny taking money from a cash register,
但有一个人确实偷了
but one of them did.
弗里德曼方法的第一步就是辨认罪行
The first step in the Friedman Method is ascertain guilt.
找出谁在撒谎
Find out who is lying.
听着  我没偷
Look, I didn't do it.
我根本没到那里去  是真的
I wasn't even there. That's the truth.
很可信  对吗
Pretty convincing, huh?
不要管他说了什么
But ignore the words.
这和他们有罪与否毫无关系
They're irrelevant.
每个人都发誓自己是无辜的
Everybody swears they're innocent,
但没有人能藏得住自己的脸
but no one can hide their face.
没有人能藏得住自己的表情
No one can hide their expressions.
最重要的一点是要让嫌犯
The most important thing is to get the suspect
直视你并重复他们的论述
to look right at you and repeat the statement
不断重复
over and over.
我们再看一遍
Let's watch it again.
我会慢放这段影片
I'm going to slow down the image.
听着  我没偷
Look, I didn't do it.
我根本没到那里去  我根本没到那里去
I wasn't even there... I wasn't even there.
-是真的  -那里
- That's the truth... - There!
就在那  看见没  他的嘴唇下方
Right there. See? Under his lip?
笑肌
The risorius muscle.
这是用来表达害怕的
It's part of the expression of fear.
当人们处于焦虑之中时
When we are experiencing anxiety,
笑肌会紧缩
the risorius muscle will become tense.
看看他有没有
Look for it.
我根本没到那里去
I wasn't even there.
-是真的  -看见没
- That's the truth. - See?
肌肉紧缩了
Clenched muscle.
好  还有一个迹象会暴露你在焦虑  前额
Good. Another telltale sign of anxiety, the forehead.
当焦虑爆发时
When there is a burst of anxiety,
这里的肌肉会变紧绷
these muscles will tighten up,
眉毛会向上扬  只有很短的时间  看见没
the eyebrows will rise upward, only for a second... see?
撒谎者想故作镇定
The liar wants to force his expressions to look relaxed,
控制自己的情绪
in control.
所以  你要找的表情
Therefore, the expression you're looking for
转瞬即逝  只有一瞬间
is fleeting, momentary.
你觉得这是真的吗  识穿骗子的方法
Do you think that's true, the way to discover a liar?
不是真的  只是蹩脚的心理学
No, it's bad psychology.
什么意思
How do you mean?
"不要管他说了什么"  真的吗
"Ignore the words"? Seriously?
不解释自己无罪的理由
How does someone prove their innocence
怎么能够证明自己的清白
without explaining why they're innocent?
而且他说只要能发觉有人在焦虑就行了
And he says it's all about detecting anxiety.
先别说你有没有罪
Well, I don't care how innocent you are,
如果被警察叫去审问
if a cop calls you in for questioning,
是个人都会焦虑的
you're gonna be anxious.
所以焦虑能证明什么
So what does anxiety prove?
如果没有警察呢
What if there is no cop?
如果在没有理由焦虑的情况下呢
What if there is no reason to be anxious?
我不知道  每个人都是不同的
I don't know. Everybody's different.
每个人有每个人的特征  我不...
Everybody's got their tell. I don't...
怎么了
What?
迪伦·诺尔斯
拳击场百货商店
卢瑟·萨尔达纳
东翼跑鞋
皮特·鲍因斯
广传电子产品商店
这不是一件小事
This isn't a small thing.
这是一起巨大的集体诉讼
This is a massive class action.
每一个身家上十亿的全国连锁零售商
Every multi-billion dollar nationwide retailer
都派了中层管理者
is sending middle-management
来参加这种研讨会  东翼跑鞋
to these seminars... East Wing Running Shoes,
广传电子  拳击百货
Widespread Tech, B&X...
我以为这些研讨会是关于警察培训的
I thought these seminars were about training cops.
这是这个研讨会的初衷
That's how they were intended,
但是零售商们用这个技术
but retail stores are using the same techniques
来对付自己的雇员
against their own employees,
而结果很可能会错怪好人
and it's just as likely to result in a false positive.
芭芭拉  你觉得怎么样
Barbara, what do you think?
是个好机会
It's good.
去定出个集体来
Go certify a class.
我们该派波比和她一起去
We should put Bobby on it with her.
现在这是件大事了
It's a big thing now.
现在是谁和她一起
Who's on it with her right now?
新来的律师  玛娅
The new associate, Maia.
是我的话会让她继续跟这个案子
I'd keep her on it.
玛娅挺不错的
Maia's good.
她很积极
And she's motivated.
-那个林德尔家的孩子吗  -是的
- That Rindell kid? - Yes.
当然
Sure.
所有人都恨她
Everybody hates her.
这是一个激发斗志的绝妙机遇
Great way to mold a fighter.
好吧
All right.
这个位置可能不会招人了
There may not even be a job here.
我只是想提醒一下你们
I just want to warn you.
你是来应聘助理职位的吗
Uh, you're here for the assistant position?
请进  你是丹妮拉吗
Come on in... Daniela?
请坐
Have a seat.
这还是你的案子  弗兰克
This is still your case, Frank,
但现在也是集体诉讼了
but it's also now a class action.
也就是说我不用付钱了
So I don't pay anything?
对  你有更大的希望
Right, and it's more likely
得到更多赔偿
that you'll get a larger settlement,
因为这些都是大公司
because these big companies
大公司都不想破坏自己的形象
will want to avoid the embarrassment.
这得搞快点
Is this going to move quickly now,
因为我现在连房租都交不起了
because I'm having trouble paying rent.
我们认为这些公司会想办法驳回上诉
We think the companies will try to win this motion to dismiss.
如果做不到  他们就会协商和解
And if not, they'll negotiate a settlement.
-好吧  我要签什么协议吗  -要的
- All right, do I have to sign something? - Yes.
你可以帮到我们  弗兰克
And, actually, you can help us, Frank.
我们要找其他和你一样
We're looking for other workers
被克扣工资的员工
who have had their wages garnished, just like you.
-如果你...  -这个案子是什么来着
- So, if you... - What is this case again?
我们要召集一群被诬陷
We're gathering a class of retail workers
偷了店里东西的零售员工
who were wrongly accused of stealing from their stores.
好了  明白了
Okay, got it.
你要回来工作了吗
So are you coming back to work?
大家都很想念你
Everybody misses you.
不了  我找了别的工作
No, I got another job.
你能帮我个忙吗
In fact, can you help me out with it?
这里的人你都认识
You know everybody around here.
这里有谁被扣了工资吗
Is there anybody in the mall who had their wages cut?
我们要对所有的混蛋大公司提起诉讼
We're bringing a lawsuit against all these big asshole companies,
我知道这里的人你都认识
and I know you know all the people here
他们的不满你都清楚
and how they complain.
有谁在抱怨自己的工钱吗
So is anybody bitching about their paychecks?
就是有人被强迫承认
It's about people being forced to confess
自己偷了衣服或者鞋子或者电脑
that they stole clothing or shoes or computers.
如果你听到了什么消息  这是我的名片
So if you hear anything from anybody, here's my card.
让他们打给我
Tell them to call me.
你在干什么  芭芭拉
What the hell are you doing, Barbara?
我在干什么  我在吃三明治
What am I doing? I'm having a sandwich.
你在拉我的会员提起集体诉讼
You're dragging my members into a class action.
如果你说的是克扣工资的事的话
If this is about the salary garnishing,
我们没有拉...
we're not drag...
你惹到管理层了
You're pissing off management!
我们正处在协商合同的节骨眼上
We're on the eve of a contract negotiation,
你却惹恼了管理层
and you're pissing off management.
是有工会成员来投诉
It was a union-member complaint.
-我们只是...  -不不不
- We are merely... - No, no, no, no.
是你们说服他
You convinced him
发起集体诉讼的
to pursue a class action,
就因为你们想要钱
because you wanted the money.
你们的人跑进我们的办公室寻求帮助
You came into our offices and asked for our help
就为了发起集体...
to collect a class...
就是她们两个
Those two did.
-你们和我们是有合约的  -没错
- Your contract is with us. - Yes.
而你们雇我们也是为了帮助成员和...
And you employed us to help your members and...
那只是做个样子而已
As a gesture, merely.
或许你们的成员想要知道这件事情吧
Uh, maybe your members would like to know that.
你是认真的吗
Seriously?
我们之间的合约就这么没有意义吗
That's how little our contract means to you?
你们居然在威胁我
You're threatening me?
天呐  如果那都算威胁  朋友
God, if that's considered a threat, friend,
我可真想活在你的纯真世界里
I would love to live in your world.
这起集体诉讼  我们一分钱都不会给
We won't pay a cent for this class action,
我们也不会提供任何协助
and we won't help in any way.
快放弃这个案子
So drop it.
你要怎么做
What are you gonna do?
我们去另找一个赞助人吧
We're gonna find another benefactor.
你手里有什么案子
So what do you have?
一个新案子  刚刚接下来的
A new suit. Very last-minute.
针对12家全国零售商的集体诉讼
Class action against 12 nationwide retailers.
我大概需要140...
I'll need financing on, say, 140...
有几个原告
How many in the class?
我们正在征集
We're gathering that as we speak,
大概有20个  可能更多
but we think 20, maybe more.
易博得同情的工薪家庭
Sympathetic, working-class families,
他们都是零售业工作人员
all retail workers.
试验案件是什么
Who's the test case?
第三页最上面
Top of page three.
弗兰克·格文  32岁
Frank Gwinn, 32 years old.
单亲父亲
Divorced father.
很适合作证  读过大学
Good witness. College-educated.
在BMI的门店工作
Worked at BMI selling shoes.
以往没有诉讼  也没有前科
No litigation in his background, and no priors.
-他有贷款没还  -那是学生贷款
- Uh, he's delinquent on a loan. - It's a student loan.
2012年申请的  现在要再次偿还了
2012. He's making payments again.
你的想法是
Your proposal?
你们资助600个工时的薪资
You finance 600 billable hours
头款要30万美元
for an initial payment of $300,000.
有两个退出时间点
You'll have two exit ramps.
一是提出驳回起诉的动议后
One, after the motion to dismiss.
二是庭审六个月后
Two, six months into trial,
前提是这官司会打这么久
if we even go that long.
你们能坐收报酬的40%
You share 40% of the award,
最高可达800万美元
up to $8 million.
不行
No.
为什么
Why?
这是最好的条件了
You can't get better.
是凯文·德拉戈法官负责审理驳回起诉的动议吧
Your motion to dismiss is in front of Judge Kevin Drago?
我们曾在他审理的案子里胜诉
We've won in front of him before.
我们的算法并不喜欢他
Our algorithm doesn't like him.
这个案子里不行
Not for this case.
你的算法并不知道
Your algorithm's not taking into account
我是个吊炸天的好律师
that I'm a fucking good lawyer.
别爆粗  好吗
Don't swear, okay?
会吓到杰
It bugs out Jer.
对不起
I'm sorry.
你们的算法喜欢这个案子吗
Does your algorithm even like this case?
喜欢
It does.
前景很好  潜在回报也很高
Good optics, good potential pay-out.
问题就是法官
It's just this judge.
没关系  我去换个新法官
It's okay, I will get you a new judge.
要怎么换
How you gonna do that?
我可是个好律师
I'm a good lawyer.
我们要上庭了
We're going to court.
去他妈的工会  我们自己出钱
Fuck the union, we will finance this thing ourselves.
你  我要你也出庭
You, I want you in court.
你叫什么来着
Uh, uh, what is your name again?
-玛娅  -玛娅  很好
- Maia. - Maia. Great.
-次席律师  -我...谢谢你  先生
- Second chair. - I... Well, thank you, sir.
只可惜我们遇到麻烦了  阿德里安
Unfortunately we've run into a snag, Adrian.
什么麻烦
What?
原告人数不足  没有工会帮忙
The class. Without the union's help,
我们很难找到那些
we're having a little trouble locating employees
被抵扣工资的雇员
with garnished wages.
去查查犯罪报告
Check crime reports.
只要有丢失的库存
Any business missing back-stock
-他们就会上报的不是吗  -不行  他们试过了
- they'd report it, right? - No. They tried that.
那就去发传单  到网上查
Let's post fliers. Let's check Reddit.
发挥创造力  我已经和资金合伙人说
Let's get creative. I've told our financial partners
会有20名原告  所以赶紧去找吧
that we would have 20 members in the class, so let's get to it,
-可以吗  -这上面有23个被其雇主
- all right? - Here's 23 employees who were accused of theft
指控偷窃并被扣薪水的员工资料
by their employer and had their wages garnished.
还有十几个备选的
And I have feelers out to a dozen more.
外面还有两个人等着进来面试
And there are two more people here to be interviewed.
她是谁
Who is that?
我的新助理
My new assistant.
凯文·德拉戈法官
你想让我回避此案
You want me to recuse myself?
很遗憾是的  法官阁下
Yes, Your Honor. Regretfully.
你不喜欢我吗  律师
You don't like me, Counselor?
不会啊  我很喜欢您
No, I love you.
在我们律所  大家都对您赞誉有加
At our firm, we speak very highly of you
一直如此  法官阁下
all the time, Your Honor.
但不幸的是  在本案中
But unfortunately, in this instance,
存在利益冲突
there is a conflict of interest.
我们没问题  法官阁下
We're good here, Your Honor.
一点问题都没有
No problem.
这不就是个驳回指控的动议嘛
Isn't this just a motion to dismiss?
我不明白我能与此案有什么利益冲突
I'm not sure how I can be conflicted out.
我在BMI的门店买过东西  也就这样
I've shopped at BMI, but that's about it.
你呢  先生
And you, sir?
我认识你吗
Do I know you?
不认识  法官阁下
No, Your Honor.
你已经尽力了  博斯曼先生
Nice try, Mr. Boseman,
但我还是要驳回你想让我回避此案的动议
but I reject your motion to recuse me.
可以开始传唤你方的第一位证人了
We can start with your first witness.
法官阁下  其实还有一件事
Actually, Your Honor, there's one more thing.
你是在挑战我的耐心  先生
You're trying my patience, sir.
最近您在一次投资中亏损了超过100万美元
Recently you lost over a million dollars in an investment.
我说得没错吧
Am I correct?
那不关你事
That's none of your business.
我的损失也和本案没有任何关系
And that loss has nothing to do with the matter here.
快坐下
Now sit down.
不幸的是  我方的次席律师...
But unfortunately, our second chair here...
玛娅  你能站起来把全名说出来吗
Uh, Maia, would you stand up and state your full name please?
玛娅·林德尔
Maia Rindell.
如您所见  法官阁下
As you can see, Your Honor,
因为您在林德尔德庞氏骗局中
since you've lost most of your savings
损失了绝大多数积蓄
to the Rindell Ponzi scheme,
所以您无法公正地判决此案
you cannot fairly judge this case.
查尔斯·阿勃纳西法官
我们在这个美好的周三下午相聚在这里
So here we all are on this lovely Wednesday afternoon.
只可惜  我恰巧没找着
And unfortunately, I have misplaced
我的处方眼镜
my prescription glasses.
所以我只能戴着这副处方墨镜了
So I will try to make do with these prescription sunglasses,
希望你们别介意我看着跟个电影明星似的
if you don't mind me looking a little bit like a movie star.
您戴着真好看  法官阁下
Very becoming, Your Honor.
没那么夸张啦
Well, I wouldn't go that far.
我来自洛杉矶  已经习惯这种装扮了
Coming from L.A., I'm used to it.
洛杉矶
Ah, Los Angeles.
你们那边旱情如何
How is your drought?
正在好转
Uh, improving.
很好  我很喜欢你们州
Good. I love the way your state
重视绿色能源的种种举措
emphasizes green energy.
是的  我自己就有一辆特斯拉
Yes, I have a Tesla myself.
真是辆好车
It's such a wonderful car.
法官阁下  我们在谈驳回起诉的动议
Your Honor, the motion to dismiss.
是的  谢谢  卢卡
Yes, thank you, Lucca.
本案中的简明事实是原告试图用
The simple fact is the plaintiff is attempting to use
其从我的委托人处盗窃400双跑鞋一案
the theft of 400 running shoes from my client's...
并非盗窃案  本次诉讼并未涉及盗窃案
Not the theft. There is no theft here.
请允许我说完  谢谢
If I could finish? Thank you.
起诉15家受人尊敬的公司
To sue 15 respected companies.
换句话说  这是个特洛伊木马
In other words, this is a Trojan Horse...
实际上  我会选用的比喻  法官阁下
Actually, the metaphor I would use, Your Honor,
-是劫贫济富的罗宾汉  -你是认真的吗
- is a reverse Robin Hood. - Seriously?
争论开始激烈起来了
Well, this is getting heated.
我的当事人一年挣四万美元
My client makes $40,000 a year.
史蒂文斯女士的委托人年入130亿美元
Ms. Stevens' client makes $13 billion.
然而每次发工资的时候
And yet every payday,
他们会从他的实得工资中扣除40%
they take 40% of his take home pay.
好了  那么战线已经很明了了
Okay, well, battle lines drawn.
史蒂文斯女士  传你的第一位证人
Ms. Stevens, your, your first witness.
我们的库房发生过很多盗窃事件
We had a lot of theft from the store-room,
今年损失了约60万美元
almost $600,000 this year.
所以我被指派来对雇员进行问询
So I was asked to question the employees.
你为什么会锁定原告呢
And why did you zero in on the plaintiff?
根据弗里德曼方法  他表现出了欺骗的迹象
He showed signs of deception per the Friedman method.
这是一种被警察用来
This is a method utilized by the police
-审讯嫌疑人的方法吗  -是的
- to question suspects? - Yes.
-被告签署了这份认罪书吗  -是的
- And the plaintiff signed this confession? - Yes.
他清楚地和我们交代了他是如何偷偷地把货箱
He told us exactly how he slipped the crates into his car,
装入了他的车里并将其运到了麦斯威尔街市集
took them down to Maxwell Street Market,
以一万美元的价格卖给了一位供应商
and sold them to a vendor for $10,000.
谢谢  帝亚蒂安先生
Thank you, Mr. Diyardian.
-那信息是他给我的  -我问完了  法官阁下
- He gave me that information. - Nothing more here, Your Honor.
迈克  你能把屏幕再多转过来点吗
Mike, could you angle that screen some more?
这幅太阳镜是偏光镜
These sunglasses are polarized.
是的  继续转  再转一点
Yeah, keep coming, keep coming. Ah.
继续  再转一点
Keep coming, keep coming.
好了
Oh, well...
请继续
Uh, continue, please.
就问你几个问题  班吉
Uh, just a few questions, Benji.
这起盗窃案你为什么不报警呢
Why didn't you tell the police about the theft?
抱歉你说什么
Excuse me?
如果是我有价值七万美元的货品被窃
Well, if it were me and I had $70,000 stolen,
我会去报警的
I would go to the police.
公司更愿意将这些事情内部解决掉
Well, the company would rather settle these things internally.
另外我更希望你叫我"帝亚蒂安先生"
And I'd rather you call me "Mr. Diyardian."
抱歉
Oh, my apologies.
那么根据你的审讯结果
And Mr. Gwinn stole this $70,000,
格文先生盗走了这七万美元货品吗
according to your interrogation?
我的问询
My interview.
是的  你的问询
Right, your interview.
在你印象里  弗兰克·格文就是个贼  对吗
To your mind, Frank Gwinn is a thief, right?
他偷东西  是的
Well, he stole, yes.
那为什么公司不解雇他
Then why didn't the company fire him?
法官阁下  我觉得BMI公司因为
Your Honor, I-I think it's a little odd that BMI
其所做出的人道主义行为而被指责有点奇怪
is being censured for doing the humanitarian thing.
我不认为原告是在指责他们
Oh, I don't think plaintiff is censuring them.
我觉得她只是很奇怪他们会留着小偷
I think she just finds it odd that they kept the thief
公继续当员工  我也有同感
on staff, as do I.
公司只是想有个能追回损失的
Well, the company just wanted an opportunity to claw back
-机会  不是吗  -没错  是的
- its losses, didn't it? - Right, it did.
所以公司继续雇佣弗兰克
So the company wanted to keep Frank employed
这样他们就能从他的工资里扣钱了
so they could take from his paycheck?
-是这样吗  -我是不会这样表述的
- Is that right? - Well, that's not how I'd put it.
那你想如何表述  班吉  别急慢慢想
How would you put it, Benji? Please take your time.
你是在暗示这其中存在不良动机
You're suggesting bad motives here.
但是BMI公司认为它的所有雇员
But BMI thinks all its employees
都应该被允许改过自新
should be allowed to make things right.
那么因此  即使弗兰克
And so, even though, Frank,
据传偷窃了七万美元的货品
supposedly stole $70,000,
他依然被允许在无监管的情况下
he was still allowed to work alone
独自一人在库房里工作吗
and unsupervised in the backroom?
反对  重复问题
Objection. Asked and answered.
实际上  不是  我想听听他的回答
Uh, actually, no, I'd like to hear the answer.
我们信任我们的雇员
We trust our employees.
这就是你为什么对他进行了七小时的问询吗
And that's why you questioned him for seven hours? -
反对  诱导性问题
Objection. Argumentative.
我换个问法
I'll rephrase.
你对我的委托人进行了多久的问询
How many hours did you question my client?
我不知道  我没计时
I don't know. I didn't keep track.
那个
Well, uh...
这上面写着七个小时
uh, it says seven hours here.
你好  卢卡  很高兴看到你还在这里
Oh, hello, Lucca. Good to see you're still at it.
而这位是  玛  抱歉
And it's um... Mai... I'm sorry,
-米娅  -玛娅
- Mia. - Maia.
-玛娅  谢谢  你好  -你好
- Maia, thank you. Hi. - Hi.
我是安德莉亚
I'm Andrea.
你家里发生的事情我深表遗憾
I'm so terribly sorry about your family.
对你来说一定很难熬
Must be hard on you.
还是可控的
It's manageable.
可控的
Manageable.
很好
Good.
女性正一点点接管这个世界
Women are taking over the world, piece by piece.
我在想我们俩什么时候可以聊聊  卢卡
Um, I'm wondering if you and I could talk sometime, Lucca.
我们现在就可以聊
We can talk right now.
我只是
Well, I-I just
不喜欢在公共场合这么做  不过
hate doing it here in a public place, but...
那么  你们的价格是多少
So, what's the offer?
价格
Offer?
不  我只是想知道你是在哪理的发
No, I-I just wanted to know where you got your hair cut.
我只是很喜欢你的刘海
I just, I love the bangs so much.
我一个朋友给我理的
A friend of mine.
-她在她的公寓里给人理发  -真的吗
- She cuts hair out of her apartment. - Really?
你能把她的电话给我吗
Could you maybe get me her number?
-当然可以  -谢谢
- Sure. - Thank you.
天啊  顺便说下  我很喜欢你这条项链
Gosh. Mm. I love this, by the way.
你戴上一定会很好看
It would look great on you.
你想买吗
Do you want to buy it?
不
No.
我宁愿把笑容从蒙娜丽莎脸上买走
I'd sooner buy the smile off the Mona Lisa.
明天见
See you tomorrow.
再见  米娅
Bye, Mia.
你妈妈来了
只是有这个担心
It was just a scare.
特罗特医生发现了另一处肿块
Dr. Trotter found another lump.
但他认为应该是良性的
But he thinks it's nothing.
-很好  -这就是你打电话的原因吗
- Good. - Is that why you called?
是的  我听说癌症
Oh, yes, I mean, I was told the cancer
转移到了你的淋巴结上
had spread to your lymph nodes.
那是我们担心的情况
Well, that's the fear.
见到你真好  玛娅
It's good to see you, Maia.
你看起来长大了
You look older.
看着我  妈妈
Look at me, Mom.
为什么
Why?
我只想问你几个问题
I just want to ask you a few questions.
玛娅  我上两周回答的问题
Oh, Maia, I spent the last two weeks answering more questions
比我这辈子答过的都多
than I have in my whole life.
是的  而我是你女儿
Yes. And I am your daughter.
我只是想再多问你几个
And I just want to ask you a few more.
看着我
Look at me.
好的  我看着你
Okay, I'm looking at you.
医生真的担心过癌症复发吗
Was there really a cancer scare?
是的  宝贝
Yes, baby,
的确有担心
there was a cancer scare.
你没有骗我
And you're not lying to me?
我是你母亲
I'm your mother.
爸爸是清白的吗
Is Dad guilty?
你知道他是清白的
You know he's not.
你呢
Are you guilty?
不  玛娅  我也是
No, Maia, I'm not guilty.
有罪的是贾克斯叔叔
Uncle Jax is guilty.
你只要相信我  宝贝
You just need to trust me, baby.
我们是一家人
We're family.
我不知道她有没有说谎
I don't know if she's lying or not.
你是说癌症的事吗
About the cancer?
不  基金的事
No, about the fund.
你觉得是你爸做的吗
Do you think your dad did it?
我不知道
I don't know.
我们家一直风平浪静
We were always the boring family.
我是说
I mean,
我朋友们...
all my friends, their...
他们的父母要么离婚
their parents were divorcing
要么外遇...
or having affairs and...
我以前还编造父母吵架的故事
I used to lie about Mom and Dad fighting,
好让自己显得不那么奇怪
so that I wouldn't seem so weird.
如今
And now...
好像在为那些年的幸福还债
it's like we're paying for all those years of happiness.
那是你父母
That's your parents.
你不必如此
Doesn't have to be you.
你可以过得很幸福
You can be as happy as you want.
我们继续
And we're back.
问题是  年轻人
Now, here's the thing, young man.
不用  都坐吧
No, you can all sit down.
我有个问题问你
I have a question for you.
什么叫旋后
What is supination?
我昨天去买跑鞋
I was buying running shoes yesterday
他们说我脚掌旋后
and they told me my feet supinate?
旋后是说
Yeah, uh, supination
你跑步时脚掌外翻
is when your feet roll outward when you run.
-这样不好吗  -可以这么说
- Oh, and that's a bad thing? - Yes, it can be a bad thing.
所以你需要更坚实的外鞋底
But that's why you need shoes with a firmer outer sole.
像这种鞋吗
Ah. Shoes like these?
法官阁下  我们有证人要请出
Uh, Your Honor, um, we do have a witness,
但如果您对原告有同情心
but if you're feeling biased towards the plaintiff,
那我们请求允许申请回避
we ask that we be heard on a recusal.
不  律师
No, no. No, counselor.
我只是寻求建议
I'm just getting some advice.
抱歉
My apologies.
脚掌旋后还是旋内  我都不偏向任何一方
I will work hard toward neither supinating
会公正审判
nor pronating toward one side or the other.
下位证人
Your next witness.
审讯者只是要让说谎者
The interviewer merely tries to ease the way
更容易承认事实而已
for a liar to admit the truth, that's all.
所以你试着简化案件
So you tend to minimize the crime?
是的
Yes.
根据帝亚蒂安的证词
According to Mr. Diyardian's own testimony,
他对疑犯说的很清楚
he made it clear to the suspect
偷盗不是大事
that the theft was not a big matter.
公司只想解决问题
They just wanted to solve it.
事实上  他能理解人为何会被诱惑
In fact, he could understand why someone would be tempted.
他自己都觉得受诱惑
He was even tempted.
原告暗示过
And the plaintiff has suggested
帝亚蒂安先生把跳蚤市场的
that Mr. Diyardian handed all the details
所有销售细节交给了弗兰克·格文先生
of the flea market sale to Mr. Gwinn?
是的  但这只是审讯法的一部分
Yes, but that's just part of our method.
让疑犯明白
Making it clear to the suspect
你知道他所有的犯罪事实
you know all the particulars of his crime
让他觉得不被发现是不可能的
helps him feel there is no way to avoid detection.
警察也是运用同样的方法
And this is the same method used by police
去抓罪犯的吗
to catch criminals?
是的  当然  此方法已经过测试
Yes, definitely. It is tried and tested.
我说完了  法官阁下
All done here, Your Honor.
你想来询问吗
Do you want to do it?
你不想的话
Well, if you don't want to.
不不  我想
No. No, I want to.
勒弗奈先生
Mr. Le Frenais.
是拉弗奈
La Frenais.
拉弗奈
在你的方法里
Is it part of your method
可以欺骗嫌疑人对吗
that you can lie to the suspect?
抱歉  律师  能大点声吗
Sorry, Counselor. You, uh... Can you speak up?
丽萨可能听不清
I think that Lisa is having problems hearing you.
当然
Yes. Of course.
先生  在你的方法里
Is it part of your Friedman method, sir,
可以欺骗受审讯的嫌疑人吗
that you can lie to the suspect being questioned?
好多了  谢谢
Whoa. Much better, thank you.
那不是我的方法
It's not part of my method.
是最高法院决定的  弗雷泽对卡普一案
It's part of the Supreme Court decision, Frazier v. Cupp.
警察可以欺骗疑犯
Police officers can lie to suspects.
那么你方法的第五步
And so in step number five of your method,
盘问者可以向疑犯展示
the interviewer is to present evidence of culpability
犯罪证据  无论真实与否
to the suspect, whether it's true or not?
当然  证据最好是真实的
Well, it's better if the evidence is true, of course.
但可以不真实
But it doesn't have to be?
没错
No.
所以当班吉让弗兰克·格文看
So when Benji presented Frank
偷价值七万美金跑步鞋的
with a DVD recording of him stealing
录像带时
the $70,000 in running shoes...
事实上录像带是空白的
a DVD that was completely blank,
顺便说一句
by the way...
你觉得这么做没问题吗
that was A-okay with you?
没问题  如果可以找出窃贼
Yes, if it helps find a crook, yes.
但用你的方法不是出现过
But doesn't your method result
虚假供述吗
in false confessions?
很少
Very few.
事实上  你的方法
In fact, hasn't your method
不是在加拿大和英格兰
been banned by police
被警方禁用了吗
in Canada and England?
不能叫被禁  他们选择不使用而已
I wouldn't call it banned. They've chosen not to use it.
因为有太多虚假供述
Oh, because it resulted in too many false confessions?
这样说不公平
I don't think that's fair.
但这是事实吧  先生
But is it true, sir?
留给大家分析吧
I'll leave that analysis to others.
分析  这...
Analysis. What...
弗里德曼方法
"The Friedman Method
这一审讯方法
"is a banned coercive technique of interrogation
导致太多虚假供述
"that results in too many false confessions.
因此在我们的司法系统中禁用
"It is therefore banned within our jurisdiction."
你是说这样的分析吗
Do you mean analysis like that?
这是谁写的
Who wrote that?
梅丽萨·斯塔
Melissa Starr.
苏格兰场的伦敦警察
London Metropolitan Police. Scotland Yard.
好的
Okay.
还有问题吗
Anything further?
没有了  法官阁下
Nothing here, Your Honor.
谢谢
Thank you.
你好  戴安·洛哈特办公室
Hi. This is Diane Lockhart's office,
我是她助理  梅丽莎  有何需要
and I'm her assistant, Marissa. How may I help you?
是港湾医院医院的安斯沃斯医生
It's Dr. Ainsworth at Harbor Hospital.
-你要给他回电吗  -麻烦了
- Do you want to call him back? - Please.
戴安  那些申请人你都不喜欢吗
Diane. You didn't like any of the applicants?
助理申请人吗
Oh, for the assistant's job?
不  我喜欢  只是我认识梅丽莎
Uh, no, I did. It's just that I know Marissa,
她很机灵  很不错
and she's on the ball. She's good.
你也会看到的
You'll see.
好吧  这是我们的和解方案
Okay. This is our offer.
我们同意支付弗兰克·格文50万
$500,000 to Frank Gwinn.
无集体诉讼
No class action.
如果贵司坚持集体诉讼
If the firm pursues a class action,
赔偿提议作废  弗兰克一毛钱没有
our offer goes away and Frank gets nothing.
对于一年赚四万块的人来说这笔钱不少了
Lot of money for a guy pulling in 40 grand a year.
你觉得怎么样  玛娅
What do you think of that, Maia?
我觉得  我们之后会再联系你
I think we'll have to get back to you.
好
Okay.
在接下来  两个小时内给答复
In the next, uh, two hours,
不然我们继续法庭见  而我会打败你们
or we go back to court, and destroy you.
史蒂文斯女士
Ms. Stevens.
-什么  -我现在就可以给你答复
- Yeah. - I have an answer for you now.
太好了
Oh. Great.
我发型师的电话号码
My hair stylist's number.
怎么办
Well?
我们得做个决定
We got a decision to make.
不  这钱都不够给我们分的
No. It's not enough money for us to take.
这不是你说了算的  客户才能决定
It's not your decision. It's the client's.
不  这是集体决定的答复
No. It's a decision for the whole class:
所有24个客户
all 24 clients.
算法显示我们要继续战斗下去
The algorithm says we stay in.
疯了吧
This is crazy.
你不能让他们去决定我们去做什么
You can't have them decide what we do.
卢卡  账单是他们付
They're paying the bills, Lucca.
你说得对  但是弗兰克需要这笔钱
Yes, but Frank needs the money.
如果我们说不  他可能最终一个子都没
If we pass on this, he could get nothing.
又或者最终得到更多
Or he could get a whole lot more.
我们走一步看一步吧
Let's just wait and see.
我只问你最后一个问题  弗兰克
I just have one last question for you, Frank.
你为什么要认罪呢
Why did you confess?
如果你没做  为什么要认罪
If you didn't do it, then why would you confess?
他做出了我别无选择的样子
He made it seem like it was the only way out.
他有我犯罪的DVD证据
He had a DVD of me doing it.
如果你明知道DVD里什么都没有
And if you knew there was nothing on that DVD,
为什么要认罪
then why would you confess?
我觉得很无助
I felt helpless.
我累了
I was exhausted.
他让我相信我只是暂时失忆了
He had me convinced that I just repressed the memory.
他说他有个证人宣誓说
He said he had a witness who swore
看到我去了跳蚤市场卖鞋
that I was down at a flea market, selling the shoes.
-你有吗  -没有
- Were you? - No.
但是他说如果我没有向公司坦白一切
But he said he was gonna give all this to the cops
他就要把这些都交给警察
if I didn't come clean to the company.
坦白一切是指
Come clean, meaning?
在他写的声明上签字
Sign this statement that he wrote up.
-你签了吗  -我签了
- And so you signed it? - Yes.
他说我能保住工作
He said that I could keep my job,
他说对我的疑虑会消散
he said that the questioning would be over.
他说我仍然有望晋升管理层
He said that I would still be on management track.
你知道每多一个人向班吉自白
Did you know that Benji gets a bonus
班吉就多一份奖金吗
for every employee he gets to confess?
反对  无事实根据
Objection. No foundation.
绝对反对有效
Uh, that is definitely sustained.
好了  我觉得
Okay, um, I think
我对此动议有裁定了
I'm ready to rule on this motion.
法官阁下  我想要盘问证人
Uh, Your Honor, i'd like to cross-examine.
这不是全面庭审
This is not a full trial.
这不过是驳回起诉动议的裁定罢了
This is merely a motion to dismiss.
是的我知道  但是这是刚到我们手上的信息
Yeah, I know, but this information just came into our hands.
我们本来希望在庭审用上它的
We were hoping to use it at trial,
但是我们认为如果我们现在就能用上的话
but we think we can save the court a lot of time and money
可以为法庭省下很多时间和金钱
if we could ask it now.
我心动了
I... am enticed.
谢谢您  法官阁下
Thank you, Your Honor.
格文先生  你入职BMI之前在哪个公司工作
Mr. Gwinn, where did you work before BMI?
很多公司  我是临时工
Various places. I worked as a temp.
有其中一个公司叫拖乐森会计师事务所吗
And was one these places Tolleson Accounting?
-有  -你在那里当过文员吗
- Yes. - You had a clerical job there?
我当这是说是了
I'll take that as a yes.
你有被要求自动离职吗
And were you asked to leave?
不是我做的
I didn't do it.
我想你知道接下来的问题了  弗兰克
Yeah. I think you know what's coming, Frank.
有一个备用金账户
There was a petty cash situation,
几百块的样子对吧
several hundred dollars?
你被控诉私自挪用吗
And were you accused of taking it?
我告诉他们钱不是我拿的
I told them I didn't take it.
然而你同意说如果他们不报警
But you agreed to leave
你就离职对吗
if they didn't call the cops?
反对  无记录
Objection, there is no record of this.
我们的调查员已经询问过此事了
Our investigators questioned this business.
是的  因为当时的经理
Yes, because the manager at the time
只和我们的调查员说过这件事
talked only to our investigator,
并签下了宣誓书
and signed this affidavit.
我没做过
I didn't do it.
宣誓书里  当时的经理宣誓弗兰克
In it, he swears that Frank took the money,
拿了那笔备用金  后来他被抓时保证
then when he was caught, promised to return it
只要他们保密  他就归还
if they kept the theft secret.
他说谎
That's a lie!
彻头彻尾的谎言
That's a complete and total lie.
好的  我会把这个信息
Okay. That is information
纳入考量
I will take into consideration.
被告有其他问题吗
Does the defendant have any more questions?
没有了  法官阁下
Nothing more, Your Honor.
除非原告还有其他问题
Unless the plaintiff has anything more,
不然我就对动议进行裁定了
I will rule on this motion.
我讨厌输
I hate losing.
你已经尽力了
It was a good effort.
这个结果会影响集体诉讼吗
Does this impact the class?
很遗憾  会的
Yes, unfortunately.
诉讼资助退出了
The litigation financiers dropped out.
我以为他说的是实话
I thought he was telling the truth.
或许吧
Well, maybe he was.
跑步鞋那部分估计是真的
About the running shoes.
知道吗  人是可以撒谎的同时说真话的
You know, people can lie and still be telling the truth.
没有人是非黑即白
Nobody's a hundred percent of any one thing.
我妈妈癌症的事情就说谎了
My mom lied about her cancer.
只是有担心而已
It was a scare.
但不是真复发
It wasn't real.
她不过是想见我
She just wanted to see me.
她寂寞了
She's lonely.
人寂寞时总会不顾一切
People get desperate when they're lonely.
你应该去看看她
You should go see her.
妈妈
Mom?
玛娅  你来干什么
Maia, what are you doing?
我想看看你怎么样
I wanted to see how you were.
好
Good.
我就要睡了
I was just going to bed.
怎么了
What's wrong?
明天一起吃早餐吧
Why don't we have breakfast tomorrow?
外面是谁的车
Whose car is that outside?
昨天有粉刷工过来  他们有一辆车没开走
Just the painters were here yesterday. They left one.
茶呢  丽诺
Where's the tea, Lenore?
这不是个好时机
It's not a good time.
你好  贾克斯叔叔
Hi, Uncle Jax.
原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供学习  禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
公告     人人视频[人人美剧]盗用本组名号  请抵制
翻译     Alex  秋乙一  Margaery  半半子七  吃冰棒
翻译     杨爱菜  dzysteven  charcie  情迷偽優
校对     某羽  free维塔
时间轴     chance-coco  大葱ALX
后期     你是不是饿得慌
总监     free维塔
最新海外影视剧下载